judicialwatch.org 2013-09-23

# JUDICIAL WATCH PRIVACY POLICY

                            JUDICIAL WATCH PRIVACY POLICY
                                                                     Last Updated: October 20, 2011
Judicial Watch, Inc. (“Judicial Watch”) wants you to know how we address privacy issues on the
Judicial Watch web site (the “Site”) and all other websites owned and operated by Judicial
Watch, Inc. Judicial Watch provides the privacy policy below (“Privacy Policy”) to explain how
your personal information will be treated by Judicial Watch. Judicial Watch reserves the right to
amend this Privacy Policy at any time. Please check back frequently in order to see changes, and
Your use of the Site constitutes your acceptance of the privacy policy, as it may be amended
from time to time.
1. Collection of Personal Information from Site Users
a) Judicial Watch may collect and/or track (1) the home server domain names, e-mail addresses,
    type of computer, and type of Web browser of visitors to the Site, (2) the e-mail addresses of
    visitors that communicate with Judicial Watch or the Site via e-mail, (3) information
    knowingly provided by the visitor in online forms, registration forms and surveys, (including
    name, address, e-mail and other personal profile data), and (4) aggregate and user-specific
    information regarding page views.
b) Judicial Watch may place Internet “cookies” on visitors’ hard drives. Internet cookies save
    data about individual visitors, such as the visitor’s name, password, user-name, screen
    preferences, the pages of a site viewed by the visitor, and the advertisements viewed or
    clicked by the visitor. When the visitor revisits the Site, Judicial Watch may recognize the
    visitor by the Internet cookie and customize the visitor’s experience accordingly. Visitors
    may decline Internet cookies, if any, by using the appropriate feature of their Web client
    software, if available; however, this may impair certain features of the Site.
2. Use of Personal Data Collected
Judicial Watch may use personally identifiable information in a number of ways, including but
not limited to:
a) To communicate with you about your account, or to communicate information about the Site.
b) To build higher-quality, more useful services, such as by analyzing usage trends, and by
    measuring demographics and interests regarding specific areas of the Site.
c) To support the operation of the Site, troubleshoot problems, resolve disputes, and to enforce
    our Terms and Conditions;
d) To inform you about products, activities and services related to Judicial Watch. You will
    have the option of opting out of further communications of this type by sending an email to
    privacy@judicialwatch.org. (Please refer to Section 7 below.)

3. Disclosure of Personal Data Collected
Judicial Watch may disclose personally identifiable information about you to Third Parties as
follows:
a) With your consent.
b) To facilitate a transaction or communication with a third party that you have initiated.
c) To Judicial Watch’s agents and advisors (such as our accountants or attorneys). We only
    disclose the personal information necessary for them to provide their services to you or to us,
    and only under strict confidentiality restrictions.
d) As Judicial Watch believes necessary to: (a) comply with law (including court and
    government orders, and civil subpoenas); (b) enforce or apply Judicial Watch’s Terms and
    Conditions and other agreements; or (c) protect the rights, property, or safety of Judicial
    Watch (and its officers, directors, employees and agents), our users, or others.
e) If you partake (or we reasonably suspect that you are partaking) in any illegal or potentially
    illegal activity. We may disclose personal information even without a subpoena, warrant, or
    other court order, to the extent we feel is necessary to inform and cooperate with law
    enforcement agencies or other appropriate authorities.
f) In aggregated form, i.e., information about multiple users collectively without identifying
    any individual user, such as the total number of visitors to a particular section in a given
    week.
g) If you provide us with your e-mail address and/or postal address, Judicial Watch may sell
    and/or rent lists containing e-mail and/or postal addresses to third parties whose professional
    and educational missions closely resemble those of Judical Watch, Inc. Judicial Watch, Inc.
    takes extreme carefulness in its decision to sell and/or rent lists. If you would like us to stop
    including your e-mail or postal address in such lists, please send us a letter to the address
    below, requesting that we remove your information from these lists. If we receive such a
    letter from you, we will act as promptly as possible to remove your information from future
    lists that we sell or rent to third parties.
                                                   2

4. Collection of Personal Data from Children
To the extent that Judicial Watch is able to determine the age of users by their submissions to, or
communications with, the Site, Judicial Watch will not knowingly (a) collect or post information
from individuals under thirteen years of age (“Children” or “Child”) without their parent’s or
guardian’s consent, or (b) provide any personally identifying information collected from
Children, regardless of its source, to any third party for any purpose whatsoever.
5. Security Measures
Judicial Watch has implemented numerous security features to prevent the unauthorized release
of or access to personal information. In particular, when a visitor provides information through
the Site, Judicial Watch offers the visitor the ability to use a secure server. The secure server
encrypts all information a visitor inputs before it is sent to Judicial Watch, and is also used to
store personal information securely.
6. Third Party Web Sites
The Site may contain links to other Internet web sites. Unless we explicitly state otherwise, we
have no control over these third party sites and their privacy practices, and this Privacy Policy
applies only to information you supply (or that we collect) in connection with use of the Site.
You should review third party privacy policies in connection with visiting the Sites.
7. Opt-Out Right
Visitors may opt-out of having their personal information collected or used by Judicial Watch,
by contacting Christian Lee via email at privacy@judicialwatch.org or via postal mail or
telephone at the address and phone number below.
8. Judicial Watch’s Right to Contact Visitor
Judicial Watch reserves the right to contact visitors to the Site.
9. Access to and Ability to Correct Personal Data
Judicial Watch may sell and/or rent lists containing e-mail and/or postal addresses to third parties
whose professional and educational missions closely resemble those of Judical Watch, Inc.
Judicial Watch, Inc. takes extreme carefulness in its decision to sell and/or rent. Upon request
via postal mail, e-mail, or telephone (during regular business hours), Judicial Watch will provide
to visitors a summary of any personally identifiable information retained by Judicial Watch
regarding the visitor and the identity of third parties who have been provided personal
information within the last year. Visitors may modify, correct, change or update personally
identifiable information that Judicial Watch has collected through the Site or may cause their
personal record to be removed from Judicial Watch’s database by contacting Judicial Watch via
                                                   3

postal mail, e-mail, or the telephone number indicated below.
10. Judicial Watch’s Right to Change Privacy Policy
Judicial Watch may change the content of our Site and Privacy Policy at any time. Please revisit
our Privacy Policy from time to time to be sure you are familiar with our current policy.
11. Contact Information
If you have any questions regarding this privacy policy or you would like to review, change,
and/or remove your personal information, you may contact us at:
E-mail: privacy@judicialwatch.org
Telephone: 1-888-593-8442
Mailing address: 425 3rd Street, S.W., Suite 800, Washington, D.C. 20024
12. Governing Law
This Privacy Policy and the privacy practices of Judicial Watch will be subject exclusively to the
laws of the District of Columbia within the United States of America. Judicial Watch makes no
representation that this Privacy Policy and such practices comply with the laws of any other
country. Visitors who use the Site and reside outside the United States do so on their own
initiative and are responsible for compliance with local laws, if and to the extent local laws are
applicable. If you reside outside of the United States, by using the Site, you consent to the
transfer and use of your information outside your country.
                                                 4
